I was late. It's okay, sweetie,
-我來晚了 -沒事，寶貝
it's not your fault. I just wanted to play
-不是你的錯 -我只想在蓋瑞家
one more game at Gary's.
再玩把遊戲
What? You did great, you called 911 right away.
什麼？你做得很好 立即打了急救電話
He looks dead. Daddy's not dead.
-他好像死了 -爸爸沒死
He's gonna be okay, right?
他會沒事的，對吧？
He had a stroke. That's not possible.
-他中風了 -不可能！
Well, the CT confirmed a ruptured aneurysm.
CT掃描證實動脈瘤破裂了
We have to operate to clip the bleeding
得做手術止血
and reduce intracranial pressure.
-釋放顱內壓 -不，他六年前中過風
They put him on diltiazem.
他在服用地爾硫䓬
We're gonna take good care of your dad.
我們會好好照顧你爸爸的
Naja Modi, 28 years old,
納吉莫迪，28歲
suffered a burn to her left hand as a result of a cooking accident.
左手有燒傷 煮飯時不小心傷到的
Are Jared and I being punished?
我和傑瑞德是在受罰嗎？
This is not a very interesting case, is it?
這個病例沒什麼意思吧？
Lesson one.
第一
Don't suggest to the head of Surgery that working with the head of Surgery
別在外科主任面前說 跟著外科主任做事
is a form of punishment.
就是在受罰
Dr. Melendez is very unhappy with Jared
梅倫戴茲醫生非常不滿意
for how he got his job back.
傑瑞德是怎麼拿回他的工作的
And Dr. Melendez is unhappy with me for taking two days off...
梅倫戴茲醫生也非常不滿意我 休了兩天假…
I don't think he wants to talk about this, Shaun.
我覺得他不想談這事，尚恩
I was an idiot.
我太蠢了
It's on the stove. Of course, it's hot, right?
在爐子上啊，肯定很燙
You wouldn't believe how often we see these types of accidents.
妳肯定不相信我們見過多少這種事故
Well, there are a lot of idiots.
蠢貨還挺多的
Okay. What do we need to do here, Murphy?
現在要怎麼處理，墨非？
A superficial partial-thickness burn
表面二度燒傷，可以保守處理
Cleanse the area, debride with soft gauze,
清理燒傷區域，用柔軟的紗布清創
and then cover with an antimicrobial petroleum dressing.
用抗菌原油敷料包好
All of which means this should heal with minimal scarring.
也就是說留個小疤就會好了
Naja, are you having chest pain?
納吉，妳胸口疼嗎？
I think I'm having a heart attack. It's hard to breathe.
我好像心臟病發了，呼吸困難
Just relax if you can.
盡可能放鬆
Put her on oxygen, a 12-lead EKG, and order a portable chest X-ray.
給她輸氧，做12導聯心電圖 並安排床邊胸部X光片
Murphy, let's move. Come on.
墨非，走吧，快點
Her vitals are stable.
她的生命徵象很穩定
What the hell's going on here?
-到底怎麼回事？ -我不知道，但是挺有意思的
DR. LIM: We've got a subarachnoid haemorrhage.
蛛網膜下腔出血
Suction. I need to isolate the aneurysm.
抽吸，得隔離動脈瘤
CLAIRE: Poor kid. Imagine finding your dad like that.
可憐的孩子 想像發現爸爸時這種情況
Well, that's exactly how I wanna die.
那正是我想死的方式
If the dad doesn't make it,
若他父親沒挺下來
the kid will always remember that moment,
孩子會永遠記得那個畫面
be traumatized by it.
留下心理創傷
Because he loves him.
因為他愛他
The idea of dying without anybody getting hurt...
沒有任何人因自己的死而傷心…
There's nothing sadder than an empty waiting room.
最令人悲傷的莫過於空蕩蕩的等候室
Okay, what do you see?
好，看到了什麼？
A bulge on the anterior communicating artery.
前交通動脈上有個腫脹物
Yeah, the ruptured aneurysm is compromising blood flow
對，破裂的動脈瘤中斷了
to the frontal lobe.
大腦額葉的供血
Prep an eleven-millimetre standard clip.
準備十一毫米的標準夾子
Are you married? Not any more.
-妳結婚了嗎？ -離婚了
Turns out he had even worse judgement than I did.
原來他比我還沒眼光
Speaking of creeps. You hear Coyle got transferred?
說到變態，妳知道柯伊爾被調走了嗎？
Yeah, I guess.
是啊，我想是吧
Just wish they'd spent the money on a pediatric trauma pod.
真希望他們把錢用在買小兒創傷艙上
They gave him a raise.
他升職了
Clip.
夾子
The EKG confirmed you weren't having a heart attack.
心電圖證實 妳當時沒有心臟病發作
I wasn't faking. I wouldn't do that.
我不是裝的，我不會那麼做
We know.
我們知道
The imaging also confirmed
圖像也證實了
that you have considerable lung inflammation.
妳的肺部炎症很嚴重
Is it possible you inhaled smoke?
妳會不會吸到了煙？
Well, I guess I must have.
肯定是吸到了
There was a minor grease fire.
當時油脂引起了一場小火
What happens now? JARED: You need a bronchoscopy.
-現在怎麼辦？ -妳得做支氣管鏡檢查
We put a camera down your throat to see how much damage there is,
要從妳的喉部插入窺鏡檢查損傷情況
and what we need to do to repair it.
看看該如何修復
But don't worry, you'll be sedated.
別擔心，會給妳麻醉的
Please don't.
不要
Oh, I'm sorry, the test is absolutely necessary.
抱歉，必須做檢查
The test is fine. But, please don't touch me.
檢查沒問題，但是請別碰我
Except for medical purposes.
除非是治療必須的
Yeah, of course.
當然
That does not make sense.
沒道理啊
A number of religions have rules about touching.
很多宗教信仰對觸碰都有規定的
I don't quite get it, but...
-我不太理解，但… -這有道理
People shouldn't touch people unless there is a very good reason.
除非有很合理的原因 是不該觸碰他人
Okay, then what doesn't make sense?
好，那麼是什麼沒道理？
The grease fire.
油脂起火
The grease fire explains the whole thing.
油脂起火能解釋所有情況
The burn, the smoke.
燒傷、煙
She told us she forgot the stove was hot.
她說她忘了爐子很燙
How can you forget something's hot when it is on fire?
若有東西著火了，怎麼會忘了很燙？
Shaun, I'm sure we would have heard more of the story
尚恩，若她不是突然以為心臟病發了
if she hadn't suddenly thought she was having a heart attack.
我們肯定能聽到更多內容
Why didn't you fire him?
妳為什麼不炒了他？
Because his story was different than yours.
因為他的說辭跟妳的不一樣
And you believe his story?
而妳信了他的說辭？
I believe your story.
我信了妳的
But you can't prove it,
但妳沒證據
and we simply can't make a policy of believing every woman
而我們不能簡單地制定政策
who files a complaint against every man.
相信每個投訴男人的女人
After a few thousand years of doing the opposite,
數千年來一直不信女人的投訴
it wouldn't kill us to overcorrect.
如今矯枉過正又有何不妥
And the fact that your boyfriend assaulted him
而妳的男友打了他
took away any leverage I had.
讓我沒了任何籌碼
I did what I could.
我盡力了
I got him to take a position where he has very little contact
我把他調到了很少能接觸到
with staff, with patients.
其他職員和病患的職位
Outreach chair.
外聯職位
And it's a lousy assignment.
還是個很糟糕的調配
Sooner or later, he's gonna quit.
他遲早會辭職的
And get a job somewhere else.
然後去其他地方工作
If you have any better ideas,
若妳有更好的主意
I look forward to hearing them.
我洗耳恭聽
DR. LIM: You're very lucky.
你們很幸運
The aneurysm was in a small communicating artery.
動脈瘤長在了一條小的交通動脈上
We were able to restore blood flow to the impacted brain areas.
我們成功修復了 受阻大腦區域的供血
He's gonna be okay.
他不會有事的
Thank God.
謝天謝地
Is this what life is gonna be like from now on?
之後會一直都這樣嗎？
Are these things just going to keep happening?
他會時不時病發嗎？
We're gonna keep him here for a few days,
他會留院觀察幾天
do some follow-up testing,
做些後續檢查
make some adjustments to his medications.
調整一下他的用藥
Hopefully we'll find out why this happened.
但願能找到發病原因
I have to go.
我得走了
Another one? Post-operative imaging showed
-又一個？ -術後影像顯示
a 26 millimeter aneurysm in the basilar artery.
基底動脈上有個26毫米的動脈瘤
That size and location,
看這大小和位置
we're looking at a high risk of rupture.
很有可能會破裂
He must have a genetic predisposition.
他肯定有遺傳傾向性
Maybe a connective-tissue disease.
或許是結締組織病
All academic till we repair it.
在修復之前一切都是空談
DR. MELENDEZ: Through the pharynx
通過咽部
and over to grandmother's house we go.
過去了，開始探險吧
There's the epiglottis and the vocal cords.
這是會厭和聲帶
I know you're not happy that I sued the hospital,
我知道你不滿意我起訴了醫院
but I'm not gonna apologize for that.
但我不會為此道歉的
That makes it simple.
這就好辦了
I did it because I want to be here.
我這麼做，是因為我想留在這
I believe I can learn a lot from you. Even from your doghouse.
我相信我能從你那學到很多東西 盡管受你冷落
I just hope you give me a chance, sir.
我只是希望你能給我一個機會
There's the carina.
這裡是氣管隆突
I'm gonna pass into the mainstem bronchus of the left lung.
接下來要進入左主支氣管
Is breaking up with your fiancee traumatic?
和你未婚妻分手算得上創傷性事件嗎？
When I saw a woman get shot,
我看見那女人中槍的時候
everyone told me it was traumatic and that I should be going home.
所有人都說這是精神創傷 說我應該回家休息
Should you be going home?
你不應該回家休息嗎？
Give me a mucosal brush
給我一個黏膜刷
for a cellular sample. Loading it now.
-取細胞樣本 -這就插入黏膜刷
How long does it take to get over a breakup with the woman you love?
從與情人分手的痛苦中走出來 需要多長時間？
I'm seeing a lot of inflammation, but no smoke damage.
我看到了大面積炎症 但是沒有油煙損傷
That makes sense.
這說得通
I thought we were doing this because she inhaled smoke?
我以為我們做這項檢查 是因為她吸入了油煙？
She said she inhaled smoke. I didn't believe her.
她說她吸入了油煙 我不相信她
JARED: Whatever the cause, the inflammation and the damage are real.
不管原因如何 炎症和損害是真實存在的
Let's get a mucosal biopsy.
我們做個粘膜活檢
If I move down here...
若我要移動到這裡…
The scope breached a bronchial wall.
氣管鏡穿破了她的支氣管壁
She's hemorrhaging. This is bad.
-她大出血了 -這很糟糕
Prep the OR.
準備手術
Type and cross two units of blood. We've gotta move.
交叉配血兩個單位，快點！
JARED: We know there was a burn.
燒傷是明確的
Was it something related to the grease fire,
氣管損害是不是跟油火有關
or a separate, coincidental injury?
或者兩者只是獨立的巧合？
SHAUN: You don't have a theory?
你是沒有想法？
Or are you refusing to talk to Jared?
還是你不想和傑瑞德說話？
I didn't answer because it doesn't matter
我不回答，是因為我覺得
until we can repair this puncture
在我們修復穿孔，防止細菌進入
before bacteria passes through and spreads an infection.
並傳播引起感染前，這不重要
That's true.
說的沒錯
Cut this suture.
剪線
Let's approximate the edges with forceps.
用鑷子吻合切緣
Are you and Jared even now?
你和傑瑞德現在扯平了嗎？
He made a mistake, so did you.
他犯了個錯誤，你也是
Exactly what mistake did I make?
我究竟犯了什麼錯誤？
SHAUN: This breach was your fault.
穿孔是你弄的
Is that traumatic?
這算精神創傷嗎？
I had breakfast by myself.
我一個人吃的早餐
Where were you?
你去哪了？
I'm sorry. Were we supposed to have breakfast this morning?
抱歉，我們今早 本來應該一起吃早餐是嗎？
I had an early consult.
我今早有個會診
Yes. We always have breakfast on Mondays.
對，我們每週一都一起吃早餐
We do? Every Monday.
-是嗎？ -每週一
Thank you.
謝謝
Well, I guess our streak has been broken then, huh?
看來我們這個習慣的持續性被打破了？
If someone punctures the bronchus
若某人在常規支氣管鏡操作中
during a routine bronchoscopy, that's a mistake, right?
穿破了支氣管，這算是錯誤，對嗎？
Well, I can't imagine how it wouldn't be.
這肯定是錯誤
Why? What did you do, Shaun?
為什麼這麼問？你做了什麼，尚恩？
I'm wondering if I need to report Dr. Melendez.
我想知道我是否要舉報梅倫戴茲醫生
Dr. Melendez did that?
梅倫戴茲醫生做的？
The protocol is very clear.
規定寫得很清楚
I need to report it.
我得舉報
But I've seen how Jared is being treated.
但是我看到他怎麼對傑瑞德的
Will Dr. Melendez treat me badly if I report this?
若我舉報了梅倫戴茲醫生 他會不會也會對我不好？
He shouldn't, obviously. But human nature being what...
顯然，他不應該這樣 但是人性就是這麼…
Human nature?
人性？
Shaun, you know what? You should make this decision for yourself.
尚恩，你知道嗎？ 這件事應該由你自己決定
In fact, you should make
事實上，從現在開始
all your decisions yourself from here on in.
所有的決定都應該由你自己來做
That's what we agreed on, right?
這是我們說好的，對嗎？
Have you considered an endovascular embolization procedure?
妳有考慮過血管內栓塞術嗎？
I have. It's a little less risky, but I haven't done as many.
考慮了，風險會降低 但是我做得不多
So, I'm not sure which way we're better off.
所以我不確定怎麼做比較好
You want me to check the roster?
妳是不是想讓我查一下名單？
See if there's somebody available with more experience?
看看有沒有更有經驗的醫生能夠勝任？
I would like to assist, but yes.
是的，我可以從旁協助
Okay, here we go.
好的，我們來看看
No, he's not available.
不，他沒法做
So make him available.
那就想辦法讓他做
I got a husband and father
身為人夫和人父
who presented with two aneurysms in the last 12 hours.
他在過去的十二小時裡 已經出現兩個動脈瘤了
I'd rather not. This particular surgeon
最好不要，那位外科醫生
was recently transferred.
最近被調職了
Not a chance.
沒門
Coyle is the best available surgeon for the job.
柯伊爾是這項手術的最佳人選
Coyle should have been fired.
柯伊爾本應該被解雇
And if he'd been fired, he wouldn't be available.
若他被解雇了 他根本不可能來做這手術
And if he wasn't available,
若他不能做
you would be the best person for the job.
妳就是這項手術的最佳人選
Our ultimate duty is to the patient.
我們應該以患者為重
No, it's not.
不，不是
You agree he should have been fired?
妳同意他應該被解雇？
Of course... Even if he was the best doctor
-當然… -就算他是這家醫院裡
in the hospital, he should have been fired, right?
最好的醫生 他也應該被解雇，對嗎？
Yes.
對
So some things have to matter more than who is the most skilled.
所以有些事情 比誰的手術技術高超更重要
If we forgive Coyle just because he's good at something,
若柯伊爾擅長於某些領域 就能因此被原諒
what does he do next?
他接下來會做些什麼？
Either he matters, or we matter.
要嘛選他，要嘛選我們
Were you upset during the procedure?
你在手術過程中感到煩惱嗎？
Did Murphy tell you that I was traumatized?
墨非告訴妳我有精神創傷？
You think that I might have almost killed a person
妳覺得我差點害死了一個人
because you dumped me?
就因為妳甩了我？
The fact that you're describing it as me dumping you
事實上，你把這件事說成我甩了你
suggests that you are upset.
恰恰說明你為此心煩意亂
Look, I'm fine, you're fine, nobody's upset.
聽著，我沒事，妳也沒事 沒人為此煩心
Great.
很好
But you do understand that I have to ask you these questions?
但是你要明白 我必須得問你這些問題
That I need a statement from you?
因為我需要你給個說法？
Yes. Here's my statement.
明白，這就是我的說法
I wasn't distracted. I didn't screw up.
我沒有分心，我沒有搞砸
Did you get all that?
妳聽明白了吧？
Your bronchus was punctured during the procedure,
妳的支氣管在手術過程中發生了穿孔
but it's been repaired. How? How could that happen?
-不過穿孔已經修復好了 -什麼？怎麼會這樣？
Why did you lie?
妳為什麼說謊？
You said that you inhaled smoke,
妳說妳吸入了油煙 但支氣管裡根本沒有油煙
So, what do you gain by lying to your doctors?
所以向妳的醫生撒謊 妳能得到什麼好處？
I wasn't lying. I was just confused, I guess.
我沒有撒謊，我想我只是混亂了
I was in a lot of pain and it was all happening so fast.
我很痛，而且一切發生的太快了
My stomach...
我的胃…
Naja, what are you feeling?
納吉，妳有什麼感覺？
It's really sore and I feel like I'm gonna...
真的很痛，我感覺我要…
Can we get some help over here?
這裡需要幫助
Four milligrams of ondansetron.
四毫克昂丹司瓊
Airway inflammation, abdominal pain, nausea...
氣道炎症、腹痛、噁心
We need a full blood panel and abdominal ultrasound.
我們需要做全套血液化驗和腹部超音波
The procedure will seal off the aneurysm,
手術會夾閉動脈瘤
but there will almost certainly be some brain damage.
但很有可能會造成一些腦損傷
Anything from mild visual or speech disturbances
從輕微的視覺障礙或語言障礙
to significant paralysis.
到嚴重的癱瘓，都有可能
But without the surgery, he'll die.
但不做手術，他會死
No.
不
I won't consent to the operation.
我不同意做手術
There really isn't a lot of choice here.
妳沒有太多選擇的餘地
Without the operation... After his first stroke,
-不做手術… -在他第一次中風後
it took him so long to recover.
他花了很長時間才康復
It was frustrating and painful for him.
對他來說，這個過程非常痛苦沮喪
But he did recover.
但是他最終康復了
He made it clear he'd never want to live compromised.
他很清楚，他不想生活在妥協中
(WEAKLY) Excuse me.
抱歉
Thank you for having breakfast with me.
謝謝妳和我一起吃早餐
My pleasure.
這是我的榮幸
People lie a lot, don't they?
人們經常撒謊，對嗎？
No, I meant it, Shaun. I'm happy to spend time with you.
不，我是認真的，尚恩 我很開心能和你共度時光
There are seven reasons that I've thought of.
我想到了七個原因
There may even be more.
也許還有更多
Do people ever lie without a reason?
人們會毫無理由地撒謊嗎？
No.
不會
Reason number six. I think you just lied.
第六個原因，我認為妳剛剛撒謊了
I think you just lied to avoid something.
我認為妳剛為了逃避某些事而撒謊
You don't like this conversation. Shaun? Shaun, I'm sorry.
-妳不喜歡這番對話 -尚恩？我很抱歉
My aneurysm patient, we're treating him
我的那位動脈瘤病人
with blood pressure meds to try and avoid a rupture.
我們在給他用高血壓藥 避免他動脈破裂
You should do an endovascular embolization.
你們應該採用血管內栓塞
He doesn't want one. It could leave him with brain damage.
他不想這麼做 因為可能會讓他的大腦造成損害
I thought he was unconscious. He is.
-我以為他沒有意識 -他是沒意識
It's amazing. I just...
太了不起了，我只是…
I don't think I'd be able to do that.
我不認為我能做到像她那樣
She's sacrificing her happiness, her future,
她犧牲了自己的幸福和未來
just because she knows... She's lying.
-就因為她知道… -她在撒謊
She's lying. It could be either reason number four, or...
她在撒謊 可能是原因四或者是…
No, she's not lying, Shaun. She loves him.
不，她沒有在撒謊，尚恩，她愛他
She doesn't love him. You haven't even met her.
-她不愛他 -你又不認識她
You haven't seen what she's like with him,
你沒見過她和他還有他們兒子
with their son... I'm not good at reading people.
-一起的樣子… -我不善於洞悉他人
Well, I am... I think people-reading
-我善於… -我認為洞悉他人
embraces personal biases.
總會包含自己的偏見
I think we should try to avoid biases.
我認為我們應該避免偏見
Knowledge of human behavior
瞭解他人的表現
can help us make informed, intuitive decisions.
可以讓我們做出有見地的，直覺的決定
My way is better.
我的方法更好
It's based on actions. She's lying.
基於行為之上，她是在撒謊
Okay.
好吧
If you love someone,
若你愛一個人
you'll do anything to prevent their death.
你會不遺餘力阻止他死
This situation, there seems to be a conflict of interest.
這個情況，好像有利益衝突
So, I would like to bring in someone else from legal to handle it.
所以我想請法律部門的人協助
Yeah, I agree.
我同意
You're an excellent lawyer, but...
妳是位傑出的律師，但是…
But what?
但是什麼？
Do you think this is my problem?
你認為這是我的問題嗎？
It's understandable.
這合乎情理
Forty-eight hours ago, we were engaged.
48小時前我們還有婚約
And now, suddenly you're supposed to be investigating me?
現在突然妳要來調查我？
Yes.
是的
And doing crazy things like expecting you
還有更瘋狂的事
to give me complete answers to appropriate questions.
比如期待你會給合適的問題 一個完整的答案
You were trusting Murphy's judgement over mine.
妳相信墨非的判斷而不相信我的
His judgement about my demeanor.
他做出關於我的行為判斷
Seriously?
真的嗎？
I asked you a question.
我就問了你一個問題
You wanted me to screw up.
妳想要我搞砸
You did screw up. So what?
你確實搞砸了，那又怎樣？
So we just deal with it.
我們只要處理它就好了
But if you can't even admit
但若你不承認
that you're not always perfect... I am not perfect!
-你不是個完人 -我不完美！
Clearly, I have made mistakes in my life.
很明顯，我的人生裡也犯過錯
But not this time.
但這次不是我的錯
That punctured bronchus was not my fault.
刺破支氣管不是我的錯
The nurse says his vital signs are stable.
護士說他的生命徵象穩定
No change. CLAIRE: That's good.
-沒有變化 -很好
It's such a great sacrifice
很大的犧牲
to respect his wishes enough to let him go.
尊重他的願望到甘願放手讓他死
You must love your husband very much.
妳肯定很愛妳的丈夫
But, there could be another explanation.
但是也可能是其他的原因
Either you love him enough to let him die,
妳可能是愛他到願意讓他死
or you hate him enough to let him die.
又或者是恨他到想讓他死
You don't know what you're talking about.
妳根本不知道妳在說什麼
There is a doctor here who harassed me.
這裡有一個醫生曾經騷擾過我
He made me feel vulnerable, worthless.
他讓我覺得自己很脆弱並且毫無價值
Neither of which I am.
其實我並不是這樣
But he never hurt me.
但他沒有傷害過我
I can't imagine how I would feel if he did.
我無法想像若他傷害了我
What I would do.
我會做什麼
What I would want to do to him.
我會想對他做什麼
What did your husband do to you?
妳丈夫對妳做了什麼？
He's a good father.
他是個好父親
No, he's not.
不，他不是
A good father doesn't hurt a mother.
好父親不會傷害母親
Payton loves him.
佩頓很愛他
All the more reason... No.
-基於這個原因那更應該… -不
Payton doesn't know anything. He never can.
佩頓什麼也不知道，他永遠不能知道
I know you're afraid he'll come after you,
我知道妳害怕他會找妳麻煩
but there are people who can help.
但有人能夠幫助妳
Payton is better off with the memory of a loving father than the truth.
擁有一個慈父的記憶對佩頓來說 比知道真相更好
Let him die.
讓他死吧
Methanol is causing her abdominal pain.
甲醇造成她腹部疼痛
She drank wood alcohol?
她是喝了甲醇嗎？
People drink whatever they can drink.
人們有什麼就喝什麼
Well, she's Muslim. Wouldn't let me touch her.
她是穆斯林，不願意讓我碰她
Religious people aren't immune to hypocrisy.
有宗教信仰的人並不對偽善免疫
There are other ways to explain the presence of methanol.
甲醇的存在也可能有其他原因
It's also produced by the liver
肝臟也會產生甲醇
when the body is exposed to certain caustic chemicals.
當身體接觸到腐蝕性化學物質
If inhaled, caustic chemicals could also inflame the lungs.
若被吸入，腐蝕性物質也會刺激肺部
And caustic chemicals also burn. So it would explain all her symptoms.
腐蝕性物質還會燃燒 這就解釋了她所有症狀
Do you happen to have a list of which caustic chemicals do all that?
你有沒有能造成所有這些後果的 腐蝕性物質的清單？
Dimethyl sulfate.
硫酸二甲酯
It's used in the pharmaceutical industry.
被用於藥業
She's a school teacher, Murphy.
-她是學校老師，尚恩 -它也用於水處理
industrial pesticides and chemical weapons.
農藥工業以及化學武器
She has no reason to be involved with
她沒有理由參與到
water treatment or industrial pesticides.
水處理或農藥工業中
But she could be a school teacher and a terrorist.
但她可以同時是老師和恐怖分子
So, what do we do?
所以我們該怎麼辦？
The surgery.
做手術
We don't have her consent.
我們沒有得到她的同意
Technically, the issue is we don't have his consent.
嚴格來說，我們是沒有得到他的同意
We go to the wife because we can't get his.
我們找他的妻子是因為得不到他的同意
The assumption being that she's operating in his best interests.
猜想是她在為了他的利益最大化考慮
Pretty sure that's not happening here.
但似乎不是這樣的
Go back to the wife, get her to change her mind
去找他的妻子，改變她的主意
or we'll take it to court.
不然我們就上法庭
Okay.
好的
Hey, you look annoyed.
妳看上去很煩惱
I'm annoyed we're sending him home to keep abusing his wife.
我擔心我們把他送回家 他會繼續對她家暴
She's a world-class liar.
她是個一流的騙子
I mean, for all we know, she wants her husband dead
就我們所知，她想她的丈夫死掉
so that she can run off with her Pilates instructor.
她就可以和她的普拉提教練私奔
I'll get the consent. Thank you.
-我會讓她同意的 -謝謝
She refused initial treatment for methanol toxicity.
她拒絕甲醇中毒的初步治療
It's ethanol. Because she's Muslim, she can't consume it.
是乙醇，因為她是穆斯林 她不能使用乙醇
She has alcohol in her system,
她體內本就有酒精
but won't let us put alcohol in her system to treat it
她卻不願意將酒精輸送到體內進行治療
because she doesn't want alcohol in her system.
因為她不想自己體內有酒精
We put her on... Dr. Murphy.
-我們對她注射… -墨非醫生
Is this part of your evidence that she's a terrorist?
你憑此就認為她是恐怖分子？
Because she's a Muslim?
因為她是穆斯林嗎？
There are billions of Muslims that aren't terrorists.
有成千上萬的穆斯林不是恐怖分子
Is that part of your evidence that she's not?
你憑此認為她就不是恐怖分子嗎？
I think she's a terrorist
我認為她是恐怖分子
because it's the easiest way to explain her symptoms and her lie.
針對她的症狀和謊言 這是最佳的解釋
Do you have a way?
你有辦法解釋嗎？
She had an accident, it scared her.
她出了意外，嚇壞了她
Maybe we scare her.
也許是我們嚇壞了她
Hell, maybe this whole place scares her.
也許這個地方嚇壞了她
There are a lot of reasons people don't tell the truth
除了犯罪活動之外
other than criminal activity.
還有很多理由會導致人們不說實話
Six other reasons.
其他六個理由
If a person comes in with a gunshot wound,
若一個人入院的時候身上有槍傷
we have to report it.
我們得上報
Why don't we have to report someone who might be making chemical weapons?
為什麼有人可能在研製化學武器 我們卻不必上報呢？
Because unfounded accusations can destroy people's lives.
因為毫無根據的指控 是會毀掉別人的人生
Well, what does it matter what people speculate
只要真相水落石出
as long as the truth comes out?
那人們推測什麼又有什麼關係呢？
Because people make up their minds before the truth comes out.
因為人們在真相水落石出之前 就已經做出了判決
Says the guy who played the race card when he needed an advantage.
這話是從一個打種族牌 佔便宜的人口中說出的
Even if you're right, she's not making bombs
即使你說的對 當她在加護病房時
while she's in our ICU.
也並沒有製造炸彈
Also, you're wrong.
還有你是錯的
Keep me posted. If she's not better in the next two hours,
若她在接下來的兩個小時沒有好轉
I wanna know.
通知我
We need you to consent to your husband's surgery.
我們需要妳同意我們給妳丈夫做手術
I said no.
我說過了不行
There's a better way, Tessa.
還有一種更好的辦法，泰莎
Leave him.
離開他
Start a new life.
開始新的生活
(VOICE BREAKING) I'm afraid.
我害怕
I know.
我懂
But this,
但是這…
this isn't the answer.
這不是答案
If you don't consent, we'll take this to the court.
若妳不同意，我們會送上法庭
We'll tell a judge what we know.
把我們知道的都告訴法官
I told you those things in confidence.
我相信妳才跟妳說的
You are not my patient, your husband is.
妳不是我的病人，妳丈夫是
Two things will happen.
有兩種可能
We will get the consent and Payton will find out the truth.
我們得到許可，佩頓會知道真相
Tessa...
泰莎…
You are stronger than you think you are.
妳比妳想的要更堅強
Your methanol toxicity is abating.
妳體內甲醇的毒性有緩和
The treatment's working.
治療有效果了
Great.
太好了
Do you think that I'll be able to leave soon?
你覺得我很快可以出院嗎？
All of your symptoms are consistent with exposure to dimethyl sulfate.
妳所有的症狀都符合 有接觸到硫酸二甲脂
I've never heard of dimethyl... Dimethyl sulfate is used
-我從來都沒聽過什麼硫酸二… -硫酸二甲脂
to make chemical weapons.
是用來做化學武器
I didn't expect this from you.
我沒想到這話是從你嘴裡說出來的
I made a statement.
我表達了我的意見
But you're different.
你不一樣
I have autism.
我有自閉症
You've experienced bigotry.
你體會過人們對你有偏見的滋味
Yes.
是的
Have people refused to serve you?
你有被人拒絕服務過嗎？
Have you seen people change their flight because of you?
你有看到過人們 因為你更改航班嗎？
Have people cursed you out before you've opened your mouth?
你有經歷過人們在你開口之前 就對你惡言相向嗎？
I'm not prejudiced, I have evidence.
我沒有偏見，我有證據
Nobody's prejudiced,
沒有人有偏見
everybody has evidence.
大家都有證據
And I'm always brown.
而我一直都是棕色人種
Maybe you're not so different.
也許你沒那麼不同
You're sweating.
妳在出汗
Perspiration is a sign of dishonesty.
出汗是說謊的一個跡象
Chest pain can be brought on by anxiety.
胸痛可能是由焦慮引起
But this time, you are having a heart attack.
但這次，妳是心臟病發作了
EKG, stat!
心電圖，立刻
The endothelial lining
血管內皮膜
had moderate inflammation that appeared acute,
緩和了急性炎症
and there was evidence of mucosal edema.
有粘膜水腫的跡象
I made no extraordinary motions,
我沒有做任何特別的處理
nor did I apply any unnecessary force.
也沒有過度施力
And yet the bronchus was punctured.
然而支氣管被刺穿了
Which is a risk, albeit a small one, with this kind of procedure.
這是這種手術的風險 儘管可能性不大
Well, thank you.
謝謝
I appreciate the thoroughness of your answers.
感謝你耐心回答我的問題
Not sure I understood it all...
雖然我也不確定我都明白了
I probably shouldn't say anything,
或許我不該說什麼
but I know you and Ms. Preston are going through something right now.
但我知道你和普萊斯頓女士 現在正經歷一些事
That really wasn't relevant. I know. I know. It's just...
-那和這一點關係都沒有 -我知道，只是…
I know she'll get through it, but,
我知道她會挺過去的，但是…
it's good you're handling it better.
你處理得更好是件好事
It's one thing to be distracted while drafting a contract,
在草擬合同的時候分心是一回事
and a whole other thing entirely doing what you do.
你所做的又是另外一回事了
DR. LIM: Inject dye.
注入染色劑
Hanging a left at the vertebral artery.
掛在左脊椎動脈上
Okay, withdrawing the guide wire.
好了，撤回導線
Inserting the platinum matrix.
插入白金色基體
I mean, sometimes you do the right thing
我的意思是，有的時候 你做了正確的事
and things get a little better.
事情會變得更好
And sometimes things still suck.
有的時候，事情依舊糟糕
Entering the aneurysm.
進入動脈瘤
Okay.
好了
Blood pressure's spiking. Wait, why?
-血壓上升 -等等，為什麼？
There's no rupture, no bleeding, no stroke.
沒有破裂，沒有出血 沒有中風
If his BP goes up any higher, he will have a stroke.
如果血壓再高點，他就要中風了
I'm terminating the procedure.
我要終止手術
Push 20 milligrams of labetalol, stat.
立刻推20毫克拉貝他樂
We need to stabilize him before we can retry the procedure.
在繼續手術之前我們得讓他穩定下來
Which means we need to figure out what we missed.
也就是說我們得弄清楚我們漏掉了什麼
This wasn't our fault.
這不是我們的錯
His BP was stable going in.
他進手術室的時候血壓是穩定的
He's been on calcium channel blockers
過去的六年裡
the last six years... Well, we missed something.
-他一直服用鈣離子通道阻斷劑… -我們漏掉了什麼
BP doesn't skyrocket for no reason.
血壓不會無緣無故就飆升的
Run a full workup.
做個全面檢查
Why would a 28-year-old
為什麼一個28歲
with no risk factors have a heart attack?
沒有任何風險因素的人 會有心臟病？
Her heart is burning.
她的心臟在燃燒
Burning?
燃燒？
From the caustic chemical.
因為腐蝕性化學物質
Murphy... It's going through her system.
-墨非… -穿過了她整個系統
Unlike thermal burns, chemical burns get worse over time.
不像燒燙傷 化學灼傷隨著時間會越來越嚴重
And it also explains the punctured bronchus.
這也解釋了她的支氣管為什麼會穿孔
The caustic chemical thinned the bronchial walls.
腐蝕性化學物質使支氣管壁變薄
You did not make a mistake.
你沒有犯錯
That's not the only explanation.
那不是唯一的解釋
But I'll shut up now.
但我現在就閉嘴
You think you have a good idea, but you're going to shut yourself up?
你覺得你有個好主意 但是你不準備說出來？
It could be caused by an infection from the bacteria that leaked,
有可能是由支氣管穿孔導致的
as a result of the puncture.
細菌感染造成的
The treatments are diametrically opposed.
若是感染的話 治療的方式是完全相反的
Antibiotics if it's infection, steroids if it's inflammation.
若是感染的話應該輸注抗生素 若是發炎的話應該輸注類固醇
If we give antibiotics and she needs steroids instead,
若她需要的是抗生素，而不是類固醇
it will suppress her immune system,
會抑制她的免疫系統
causing the infection to flourish and kill her.
加重感染，使她喪命
If she needs steroids and we give her antibiotics, then...
若她需要的是類固醇 而我們給她輸注抗生素，那麼…
I get it, we better be right. Yes.
-我明白，我們最好是對的 -是的
Sir, I think we should bring another senior attending in
長官，我們應該 再找一位高級主治醫生參與
to consult on this decision. Why?
-商量這個決定 -為什麼？
Because if Shaun's right, you're exonerated.
因為若尚恩是對的，你就沒做錯
And if I'm right, you may have made the mistake
若我是對的，你可能犯了一個
that could kill this woman.
可能會害死這位女士的錯誤
You don't think I can be objective?
你覺得我不能保持客觀？
I think you're incredibly professional...
我認為你非常專業…
Shut up, Jared.
閉嘴，傑瑞德
It is possible that I screwed up.
有可能是我搞砸了
Let's put her on broad spectrum antibiotics.
給她輸注廣效抗生素
You're wrong.
你錯了
Making a decision on the assumption you made a mistake is a mistake.
在你犯錯的前提下做決定是個錯誤
You're very arrogant.
你很自大
It helps you be a great surgeon.
這幫你成為更好的外科醫生
Fortunately, I don't need your approval.
萬幸的是，我用不著你來批准
We've determined what the underlying problem was.
我們確定了潛在的問題
What caused your husband's aneurysm to rupture,
是什麼導致了妳丈夫的動脈瘤破裂
and why his blood pressure spiked in the OR.
以及他在手術室血壓上升的緣由
According to his labs, he hasn't been taking his meds.
數據顯示，他沒有在服用藥物
As far as I know, he has.
據我所知，他有吃藥
I mean, that's just not like him.
這不像他
We don't think it's like him either.
我們也覺得不是他
You think I had something to do with this?
妳們覺得是我動了手腳？
That I what?
怎麼？
Threw his meds away?
我扔了他的藥嗎？
He'd just order more.
他會再訂一些
But if you emptied his capsules
但如果妳清空了他的膠囊
and filled them with sugar, or even better, salt...
並換成糖，或者更好，換成鹽…
It would end your nightmare.
這將會結束妳的噩夢
I was willing to let him die.
我很願意讓他死
But I could never...
但我怎麼可能…
If I were strong enough to kill him...
若我有足夠勇敢去殺他…
Is there a chance your son knows more than you think he does?
有沒有可能 妳兒子知道得比妳以為的多？
Her heart rate's 90.
她的心率是90
That's in the normal range.
那在正常範圍內
But it was 83. It should be going down.
但之前是83，應該降低才對
All her other signs are normal.
她其它徵象都正常
You were right, this is the proper treatment.
你是對的，這是正確的治療方案
I'm switching her to steroids.
我要換成類固醇
If we give her steroids, it will suppress her immune system,
如果給她注射類固醇 那會抑制她的免疫系統
causing the infection to flourish...
導致嚴重感染…
I'm gonna push 40 milligrams of methylprednisolone.
我要注射40毫克甲基培尼皮質醇
And she'll die.
她會死的
This is on me.
我來承擔
I know.
我知道
We switched her to methylprednisolone.
我們給她換成了甲基培尼皮質醇
It's working.
起作用了
You were wrong.
你錯了
Yeah, I got that.
是的，我知道
Just about the treatment choice. You didn't do anything wrong
只是治療方案錯了
in the OR. Don't kiss my ass.
-你在手術室裡沒做錯 -別拍我馬屁
Jared saved her life.
傑瑞德救了她
If he hadn't acted so quickly, she would've died
若他沒有迅速採取措施 她可能就死了
and that would've been your fault.
而那會是你的錯
Yes, it would've. You should thank him.
-是的，沒錯 -你應該感謝他
Thank you, Dr. Kalu.
謝謝你，卡盧醫生
Hey. Can I help you?
有什麼事嗎？
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
我是尚恩墨非醫生
You're my new neighbor. Number 34.
你是我的新鄰居，34號
Yeah. Cool.
好吧
Do you wanna come in for a beer? No.
-你想進來喝瓶啤酒嗎？ -不了
Nice work.
做得好
You, too.
妳也是
You can have the honors.
功勞屬於妳
This is the first time I'm not looking forward
這是第一次，我不想告訴家人
to telling the family it went well.
手術進行得很順利
You're going to be fine.
妳會沒事的
The treatment worked?
治療見效了？
The second one did. The first one almost killed you.
第二次的見效了 第一次的差點害死妳
The fact that you're alive right now is evidence
妳現在還活著，就足以證明
that you were working with dimethyl sulfate.
妳接觸了硫酸二甲酯
You're a terrorist, aren't you?
妳是不是恐怖分子？
My brother works for a drug company.
我哥哥在藥廠工作
They use dimethyl sulfate to make one of their medications.
他們用硫酸二甲酯來製藥
He stole some for me.
他替我偷了一些
So you could make a chemical weapon.
讓妳來做化學武器
So I could make perfume.
讓我做香水
Smell that.
你聞
It's beautiful.
好香
But very stupid.
但很蠢
Yeah.
是啊
Especially since my brother would get fired if anyone ever found out.
尤其是若被發現 我哥哥會被炒魷魚
You believe her?
你相信她？
Protecting someone.
保護某人
Reason number three.
第三種理由
So, we good?
我們沒事了吧？
The thing is, I'm not sure it really matters.
問題是，我不確定這是否重要
I've been told I can only have three residents next year.
我被告知，我明年只能有三位住院醫師
That's great. Not really.
-這太好了 -不算是
Because of Coyle's transfer, I have to take on his.
因為柯伊爾走了 我得接手他的住院醫師
Reznick?
瑞茲尼克？
She's a pain.
她可讓人頭痛
Pain can be a hell of a motivator.
頭痛也可以轉化為動力
Good luck.
祝你好運
You were right.
你是對的
And I think you were right that I wanted you to be wrong.
你是對的，而我希望你錯了
And I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
You were right, too.
妳也沒錯
I kept telling myself that I'm fine, but,
我一直告訴自己，我沒事，但是
it's been hard.
這很困難
Got me second-guessing myself,
讓我懷疑自己
maybe affecting my judgement, I don't know.
也許影響了我的判斷，我不知道
If we’re hurting so bad, maybe we made a mistake.
如果我們這麼難過，也許我們做錯了
No.
不
It just means that what we had mattered.
這只是說明我們曾經擁有的很重要
It doesn't mean that it was right.
不代表那是對的
I've also been thinking that
我也在想
arrogance does make me a better surgeon.
自大讓我成為了更好的外科醫生
But it's not gonna make me a better husband.
但不會讓我成為更好的丈夫
I'm sorry.
對不起
Kristin?
克麗絲汀？
Hey, I'm Claire.
我是克萊兒
Hi. Thanks.
謝謝妳
I am doing some research on Dr. Coyle.
我在調查柯伊爾醫生
On the women who worked with him and then quit.
調查和他共事但辭職的女性
I got another offer at SF Muni.
我接到了舊金山市立醫院的工作邀請
I was harassed by Dr. Coyle.
我被柯伊爾醫生騷擾了
And I think you were, too.
我覺得妳也是
Doing the right thing can make things a little better.
做正確的事，能讓事情變得更好
Especially if we do it together.
尤其當我們一起做的時候
Yeah.
是啊
I have a new neighbor.
我有新鄰居了
So, can we have breakfast tomorrow?
我們明天能一起吃早餐嗎？
I'd love to, Shaun, but...
我很想，尚恩，但是…
We, um...
我們…
We talked about this, right?
我們說過了，對吧？
I said that I would back off if you stayed, right?
我說了若你留下，我不會繼續緊逼
More space, less fathering? I don't need a father,
-給你更多空間，不再試圖當你的父親？ -我不需要父親
I hate fathers.
我討厭父親
Right, so... I need a friend.
-是的，所以… -我需要朋友
Shaun, I am someone who can't help but give advice.
尚恩，我忍不住會給他人建議
You know, I don't know if I can not do that.
我不知道自己能否做到
So, you think I can change and you can't?
所以你覺得我能改變，但你不能？
I think that we have a certain kind of relationship,
我覺得我們的關係很特殊
and we can call it something different if we want,
如果我們願意 可以將之稱其為其它的
but we can't magically make it different.
但我們無法改變它
You said that you wanted space, you said that you needed space.
你說你想要空間 你說你需要空間
I think you should be my friend.
我覺得你應該當我的朋友
Shaun...
尚恩…
Okay.
好吧
LEA: What are you smelling right now?
你現在聞到什麼？
Pine trees.
松樹